Campbell, Ralph, Papers /3041
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Ralph Campbell Papers
1952-1964
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Campbell, Ralph
/3041
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Collection includes arbitration decisions and material on Executive Leadership training.
3074704
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, December 23, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, February 21, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Ralph Campbell (March 7, 1910 July 25, 1971) was professor of industrial and labor relations at Cornell University's School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of Rutgers University (BA, 1931), Campbell served in World War II before completing his MBA at the Harvard Graduate School of Business Administration in 1947. In 1948, Campbell joined the faculty at Cornell's School of Industrial and Labor Relations, and in 1956, he joined the faculty of Cornell's School of Education.
Campbell served the university in many administrative capacities over the course of his career. He directed the ILR School's Extension Division from 1948 to 1956, and again from 1960 to 1963. From 1956 to 1958, he directed Cornell's Summer Sessions, and from 1958 to 1960, he led the ILR School's Department of Human Resources and Administration. Nationally, Campbell was active in the National Institute of Labor Education, National University Extension Association, American Arbitration Association, the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, among other organizations.
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor Ralph Campbell: http://ecommons.library.cornell.edu/handle/1813/18574
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3012: Alice Cook Papers /4297: ILR School Biography Files 5588: David L. Cole Papers 6004: NAA Additional Records
Campbell, Ralph N. (Ralph Norton), 1910-; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3074704
- Manual For Exhibition Teachers - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Hospital Organization, Supervision and Personnel Administration, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Bound
- Harvard Business School For Private Distribution only, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Harvard Business School for Private Distribution only, 1931-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cornell University Business Leadership course for American Airlines Program Summary, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Trojan Horse, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Trojan Horse, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Wartime Manpower Mobilization a Study of World War 2 Experience in the Buffalo-Niagara Area, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Effective Executive Leadership The Eight Program of Human Relations in Administration, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Airlines (1st Revision), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Binder Misc., 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous, 1957-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Readings in Program Planning and Budgeting Office of Training and Development N.Y.S. Department of Labor, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- American Airlines, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- American Airlines Study, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Short Course Units 1-10, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Short Course Units 11-, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Harvard University Graduate School of Business Administration, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with Dean McConnell, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Training Directors Conference, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Outside Programs and Conferences, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- ILR Programs and Conferences, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Values, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Arbitration: Armstrong Cork [folder 1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Arbitration: Armstrong Cork [folder 2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Arbitration: Associated Transport (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Arbitration: Consolidated Block (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Arbitration: Continental Can [folder 1 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Arbitration: Continental Can [folder 2 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Arbitration: Continental Can [folder 3 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Arbitration: Ekco Products (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Arbitration: Ross Heat Exchangers (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Arbitration: Shuron Optical (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Arbitration: Super Food Services (Box 3, Folder 11)